Well, to show you that, I do need to
show you an additional piece of code.
And I considered teaching this at
several points during the course, but I
felt like it just fit in the best here.
But you can use this in many, many, many
different places. And this code is
called the try catch. What it does is it
tries to run a certain amount of code
and then if it can't, it does something
else instead. So, for example, if I
boy console.log log um and I said let's
console.log myv val.2 string. You can
see I've never even defined my val. So
I'm trying to cons turn something into a
string that doesn't even exist and then
I'm trying to log it. So if I save it
and I come over here I get an error and
it says my value is not defined. So over
here what I could do is I could say
let's use try and catch to handle that
error. So I'm saying try
to handle the error. If there's an
error, here's some code to run instead.
And so this is kind of like an if
statement for errors. Says if an error
happens, do this instead. So your code
will attempt to run line 12. And if it
fails, it'll run line 14. So I could say
console.log,
please call help call the help desk. So
if I save that and I come over here,
rather than my code crashing and
throwing a error, it didn't crash and
instead it said please call the help
desk. And that is the great part about
try and catch. Um
try tries to do the code and catch
catches the code. And as a matter of
fact, catch you can actually put
parentheses after it and it will receive
the error that happened. So then you can
log out that error. So I could log out
um a formatted string here
and I could say the code is experiencing
difficulties.
Please call the help desk and tell them
you are experiencing
um this error.
And then because it's a formatted
string, I can put in the error that I
received from this catch statement. So
if I save this and I come over here, it
says the code is experiencing
difficulties. Please call the help desk
and tell them you're experiencing this
error. Reference error, my val is not
defined. And so it neatly makes sure our
code still keeps running. The error is
still caught and we can handle it later.
And this actually helps when we are
handling rejection.